Imagine you and I get into a spaceship
and fly to the next closest star. It's
nearly 40 trillion km away, a distance
that could fit almost 29 million of our
sun, which means we're traveling for
75,000 [music]
years. And that's just average between
stars in the solar system. But if we
shrink down to the size of one of the
tiniest fundamental particles in
physics, the space between the stars
would be like the space between the
nucleus of individual atoms to us now.
which means we can zoom through the
atoms of solid rock as easily as flying
between the stars in space. This is what
it's [music] like to be a nutrina. They
call them ghost particles. A 100
trillion of them are flying through your
body every second and you never know it.
And we really want to detect them
because they fly straight to us unlike
other things that get blocked and warped
by whatever's between their source and
us. So nutrinos are a great way to learn
about what's out there. But how do you
detect something that can basically fly
through any detector? You build a very,
very large machine.